Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Katsuragi, it's me.
I've probably put you through a lot of trouble
by the time you're listening to this.
I'm sorry.
Tell Ritchan I said I'm sorry too.
Also, since I've troubled you
so much anyway,
there's this flower I've been growing...
It'd make me happy if you'd water it for me.
Shinji knows where it is.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Go forward without any hesitation.
If I ever get to see you again,
I'll say the words I wasn't able
to say eight years ago.
Bye.
The phone that won't ring...
Sorry,
but don't
bother me.
Working
Miss Misato's still cooped up today.
Do not enter without permission.
If you do,
I'll kill you!
Asuka...
I wonder if she won't be coming
back again today?
She won't go to school and
she won't go back home.
She just keeps playing games.
Hikari?
What is it?
Wanna go to sleep?
Okay...
I'm sorry. Am I a bother?
No, not at all.
I wasn't able to win in my Eva.
I'm not worth anything anymore.
Not anywhere.
I hate it. I hate it all. I hate everyone.
But what I hate the most is myself.
Somehow, I feel like nothing matters anymore.
I think it's okay for you to do whatever
you want and I won't say anything,
because I think you did your best, Asuka.
I see, so she passed away.
Yes, probably, even cats eventually
reach the end of their lives.
Don't cry anymore, Grandma.
I will. When I get some time,
I'll come home for a bit.
I haven't visited Mother's grave
in three years either.
I'll call you next time.
Okay, I'm hanging up now.
So, she died.
EPISODE 23
TEARS
It is impossible for us to recover
the Lance of Longinus.
Why did you use it?
We still do not have the planned number
of the Eva series.
I made destroying the Angel my first priority.
It was an unavoidable situation.
Unavoidable, was it?
You should make your excuses
more convincing than that.
Your recent actions have become intolerable.
Fuyutsuki, we're in the middle
of deliberations here.
All right.
An Angel is currently drawing near.
Let us continue this at another time.
If your seat is still waiting for you, that is.
Ikari... Does he intend to betray Seele?
I'll be there in fifteen minutes.
Launch Unit 00 from Number 32.
Send Unit 02 as backup.
That's right, Commander Ikari's orders
still stand for Unit 01.
I don't have the authority to lift
the suspension on it.
Bye.
Visual confirmation of the Angel...
Unit 00 launched, heading for intercept point.
Unit 02 on standby at current location.
No, launch her.
Commander!
It doesn't matter. She can at least
serve as a decoy.
Yes, Sir.
Eva Unit 02, prepare for launch.
Here I am, shamelessly back in the pilot's seat.
I'm so bad at letting things go.
Unit 02, please go to Gate 8.
Launch as soon as your deployment
position has been determined.
I'll only be in the way, even if I go out there.
Target approaching. It has crossed
the Gora Final Line of Defense.
I don't care anymore.
Target hovering over Ohwakudani,
continuing to rotate in place.
Target's AT Field is still active.
What were you doing?
L won't waste time on excuses.
What's the situation?
We've been in a persistent deadlock.
Pattern cycling from blue to orange!
What does that mean?
Magi indicates it cannot find a solution.
We don't have enough data
to come to an answer.
But one thing's certain.
That shape isn't a fixed form.
So we can't make the first move.
Rei, we're going to wait and watch for a while.
No, it's coming.
Rei, counter it!
It's no use! She won't make it in time!
Target is in physical contact with Unit 00!
How is Unit 00's AT Field?!
Operational, but the Angel is eroding it!
The Angel is aggressively seeking
to make first contact?
With Unit 00?
Danger!
It's invading Unit 00's organic pans!
Launch Eva Unit 02!
Send her to rescue and back up Rei!
Target making further inroads!
This is dangerous.
Over five percent has been
biologically fused already.
Asuka, close your distance by 300,
deploy your AT Field at maximum,
and fire the Palette Gun into the target's rear!
Got it? Eva Unit 02, lift off!
Move out, Asuka. What's the matter?
What's wrong with Unit 02?!
It's no good! The synch rate
is in the single digits!
Asuka!
It won't move. It just won't move!
She'll only be a sitting duck out there!
Bring her back! Quickly!
Who's there?
Me?
The me inside the Eva.
No, I can sense that there's
someone other than me.
Who are you?
An Angel? The person that we call an Angel?
Won't you become one with me?
No. I am me. I am not you.
I see, but it's no use. It's too late now.
I'll share what's in my heart with you.
I'll share this feeling with you.
Doesn't it hurt? See?
Doesn't your heart ache?
Hun? No, you're wrong. It's...
...loneliness?
Yes, it's loneliness, isn't it?
Loneliness? I don't understand.
You hate being alone, don't you?
There are so many of us, and yet,
you hate being alone.
That is what loneliness is.
That is what is inside your heart.
That is your own heart, overflowing with sorrow.
These are tears?
The one crying is me?
Rei!
The suspension on Unit 01
has been lifted as of now.
Send him out immediately.
Send him out.
Yes, Sir.
What? You didn't send him out for me.
Deploy your AT Field. Rescue Rei immediately.
Okay!
Ikari?
This is my heart wanting to
become one with Ikari?
No.
The AT Field has been reversed!
It will be eroded away at once!
Does she intend to contain the Angel?!
Rei, abandon the Eva and get out of there!
No.
If I go, the AT Field will disappear.
So, I can't.
Rei, do you mean to die?
The core is collapsing!
Critical point exceeded!
Target has been destroyed.
At this time, this operation is officially over.
Change our status to Class One Alert.
Roger that. Switching immediately
to Condition Yellow.
What about Unit 00's status?
Ejection of the entry plug
has not been confirmed.
Hurry the rescue operation for the survivor.
If there is one, that is.
No antibiotic substance from the 16th Angel
has been found thus far.
We will continue searching.
Level C traces are spreading towards the southwest.
Dr. Akagi!
What happened here will be
classified top secret.
Take back the plug. Dispose of everything else.
Roger that.
Let's get to work! Quickly!
{THE 3RD ANGEL
{SACHIEL
At last, we have defeated up through
the 16th Angel.
{THE 4TH ANGEL
{SHAMSHIEL
{THE 5TH ANGEL
{RAMIEL
{THE 6TH ANGEL
{GAGHIEL
{THE 7TH ANGEL
{ISRAFEL
{THE 8TH ANGEL
That leaves only one Angel described
in Seele's Dead Sea Scrolls.
{SANDALPHON
{THE 9TH ANGEL
{MATRIEL
{THE 10TH ANGEL
{SAHAQIEL
{THE 11TH ANGEL
{YROUEL
{THE 12TH ANGEL
{LELIEL
{THE 13TH ANGEL
{BARADIEL
{THE 14TH ANGEL
The promised time is near.
{ZERUEL
{THE 15TH ANGEL
{ARIEL
{THE 16TH ANGEL
{ARMISAEL
Our journey has been long and the
sacrifices have been great.
Indeed, first, the Lance of Longinus,
and now, the loss of Unit 00.
We have more than enough reasons
to relieve Ikari of his command.
That man is smart enough
to know the significance
of why we allowed Fuyutsuki to return safely.
We need another human sacrifice
to counter Ikari.
And we need someone who knows the truth.
Shinji, I'm coming in.
Miss Misato, the tears won't come.
I feel sad, but the tears just won't come.
Shinji, this is about all I can
do for you right now.
Stop it!
Stop it, Miss Misato.
I'm sorry.
But he must be feeling lonely.
Is he afraid of women?
No, he's afraid of being intimate with people.
Pen Pen, come here.
I see, it doesn't matter who.
I am the one who is lonely.
Yes, hello?
What did you say?!
Shinji!
Dr. Godai of Internal Medicine 1, Dr. Godai.
Please contact Conference Room 2 immediately.
Ayanami!
Neurosurgery 1
Surgery 3
2nd Floor Ward
Diagnostic Radiology
X-ray Information Desk
I'm so glad you're okay.
I guess my dad's not here.
Thank you for saving me.
What do you mean?
What do I mean? You sacrificed
Unit 00 to save me.
I see, so I saved you.
Yeah, you don't remember?
No, I just don't know.
Because I think I'm probably the third one.
Ayanami
These are tears?
This should be the first time I've seen them,
but I feel like this isn't the first time.
Am I crying?
Why am I crying?
That's right. The First Child will be
maintained in her current condition.
There is no need for new restrictions.
The same goes for the Second and the Third.
They only need to be watched.
But Chairman Kiel and the rest will raise
a fuss when they learn that Rei is alive.
I have offered something else
to Seele's old men.
We needn't worry.
We would like for things to proceed smoothly.
We do not wish to subject you to
any more degradation and suffering.
I do not feel humiliated whatsoever.
A strong-willed woman.
I can understand why Ikari
would want you by his side.
But the person who handed you to us
is none other than Ikari.
He refused to hand over the pilot
of Unit 00 for questioning.
He sent you as a substitute, Dr. Akagi.
I was sent in place of Rei?
Sorry,
but don't
bother me.
Working
This is a part of the truth that you wanted.
I devised thirty-six other ways
to send it to you,
but you probably won't get them.
The only definite one is this capsule.
This is everything I have to offer.
Do with it as you see fit.
The password is our very first
memory together.
Bye, take care.
The phone that won't ring,
I won't let it irritate me anymore.
Because I've accepted your feelings.
Are we certain we did the right thing
concerning Dr. Akagi?
She is different from Fuyutsuki.
Returning her is in our best interest.
She has rendered distinguishing service
to the Eva series.
She can be of some use to us right now.
Indeed, for the sake of mankind's future.
Eight Evangelions are already being prepared.
Which leaves four more.
The annihilation of New Tokyo-S will be good
material upon which to advance our plans.
Hurry their completion.
That will be our promised day.
Yes, hello?
Just listen to me.
I've released the restraints placed on you.
You should be able to go outside now.
Miss Ritsuko?
It's no use, not without my pass.
I see. It's Kaji's handiwork, isn't it?
You're going to let me see the secret
in there with my own eyes.
Fine, but he's coming too.
Fine.
This looks just like Ayanami's room.
This IS Rei Ayanami's room.
This is where she was born and raised.
This place?
Yes, this is where she was born.
The water and light that form
Rei's subconscious
must have a strong impression of this place.
Dr. Akagi, this isn't what I came here to see.
I know, Misato.
Evas?!
The very first ones.
They are the failures.
They were scrapped ten years ago.
A graveyard for Evas...
It's just a garbage dump.
This is also where your mother disappeared.
You may not remember it, but I believe
you were also watching
the very moment your mother vanished.
Ritsuko!
So, this is the source of the dummy plugs?
I will show you the truth.
Rei Ayanami?
You're not saying the Evas' dummy plugs are...
That's right, the part that becomes
the core of the dummy system,
and this is the manufacturing plant for it.
This is?!
These are just dummies.
And nothing more than pans for Rei.
Man found God and in their joy,
tried to make Him theirs.
That's why there was divine retribution.
That was fifteen years ago.
The God they found had also
disappeared by then.
But then, they tried to resurrect
God on their own.
The result was Adam.
And imitating God, they created
people from Adam.
The result was the Evas.
People? They're human?
Yes, they're human.
The Evas do not intrinsically have souls,
but they have human souls embedded in them.
They were all salvaged.
The only vessel that contained a soul was Rei.
She was the only one born with a soul.
The Chamber of Gaf was empty, you see.
These things here that look like Rei
have no souls.
They're just vessels.
That's why I'm going to destroy them.
Because I hate them.
Do you know just what you're doing?!
Yes, I know. I'm destroying them.
They're not people.
They're things shaped like people.
But I lost, even to these things! I couldn't win!
I only needed to think of him,
and I could endure any kind of humiliation!
I didn't care what happened to my body!
But he... He...
And I knew too.
I'm a fool!
Like mother, like daughter,
we're both big fools!
If you want to kill me, do it.
No, I would be happy if you would do it.
That would be truly foolish of you.
The tragedy of the people
possessed by the Evas...
But that goes for me too.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
The city disappears, his friends leave.
A boy smiles upon the timid Shinji.
Shinji gives himself over to the smile
that is like a soothing breeze.
But a cruel fate was in store for them.
Next time: "The Final Messenger"
The Final Messenger